

Nicholas A.Kelly
Laehrstrasse 6
Berlin, Germany 14167
02-02-1981
eiliyasx@gmail.com
01623327520
de.linkedin.com/pub/nicholas-kelly/44/618/601
www.eiliyas.com

With a history of independent art/music activity Nicholas has brought concept, new thoughts and perspectives to the forefront of the consciousness of those whom have experienced his work. Directly and indirectly presenting a new way to view things, another way to accomplish goals. Always curious and explorative. He is currently enrolled in Berlin Startup Institute to transition into UX Design.

*Holds a German Working Permit

-Experience

(October-November 2014 Berlin, Germany)
Berlin Startup Institute
Studying UX/UI Design
Scrum
HTML5 CSS3
Javascript

http://students.startupinstitute.com/2014/berlin/fall/product-design/1015/NAKelly/

- -Freelance Designer
- Logo, Flyer and Poster Design Using Photoshop and Illustrator
- Video Editing using Final Cut Pro
- Sound Design and Composition using Hardware and Various Instruments

(Nov. 2012-2014 Berlin, Germany)

Mixtape Menage

- Created event concept which was cost effective yet created a new platform for artists and organisations to present themselves
- Fostered community activity through musical activity in a casual environment
- -Event
- -Recruiting guests
- -Hosting Show
- -Radio DJ
- -Graphic Design

http://berlincommunityradio.com

(October 2013-Current Berlin, Germany)

Sober

- Conceived, curated and promoter
- Reviewed submissions and all content for the program which holds a focus of varieties of experimental musics
- Facilitated contact and arrangements with hosting venue
- Initiated all promotion and community interaction
- -Event Management
- -Curating Performers
- -Graphic Design
- -Performer

(November 2013 Berlin, Germany)

Glitch

- Designed images that represented the conceptual direction of the event.
- -Poster Design
- -Freelance

(March-April 2013 Berlin, Germany)

A Cabaret Story

- Designed logo and Edited promotional video for premier english speaking Cabaret in Berlin.
- -Freelance

http://www.acabaretstory.de

(March-August 2010 Atlanta, GA)

C-MiniVideoArt Fest

- Conceived, Organized, Curated, Planned and Produced this event
- Obtained Fiscal Sponsorship through Fractured Atlas
- Reviewed submissions and all content for the program
- Facilitated contact and arrangements with hosting venue
- -Organizer
- -Artist
- -Curator
- -Event Planner

http://www.pd.org/~eyedrum/calendar/?eventTypeId=1&id=3656&month=8&year=2010

(October 2008-October 2009 Atlanta, GA)

YEAH TV

- Directed and edited the pilots as well as recruiting guests and cultivating aesthetic direction
- -Director/Editor
- -Recruiting Guests
- -Design

(1997-2002 Macon, GA)

Cabiness Video Productions

- Filmed various events using a variety of professional cameras
- Edited Video using editing hardware of the time
- -Cameraman
- -Video Editor

Arts and Music Portfolio

www.Eiliyas.com www.soundcloud.com/eiliyas

-Electronic Composer

(2001-2014)

• Various Musical Releases Vinyl, Digital, Cassette Has performed throughout U.S., Canada, and Europe

(December 2009 U.S. Magazine)

Personal Music Included on the Under the Radar Magazine Sampler http://www.undertheradarmag.com/issues/issue_29_-_year_end_2009_-_best_of_the_decade/

-Education

(October 2014-November 2014) Berlin Startup Institute (UX Design)

(2003-2005) Georgia State University (Fine Art/Graphic Design)

(2001-2002) Savannah College of Art and Design (Film/Sound Design)

-Selections and Presentations

(October 2014 Berlin, Germany)

Presentation at MusicTechFest Berlin

Presented brief summary of alternative musical interface and how it was developed

(April 2013 Albuquerque, New Mexico)

Video Art Selected for the Experiments in Cinema Festival

Video Art Work "PoemEnd" selected

(July 2012 Bath, U.K.)

Presentation for

"MIX: A Conference Exploring Transmedia Writing and Digital Creativity"

Based on abstract titled "The Necessity of New Media and it's Governing Vocabulary"

(September 2011 Pori, Finland)

Artist Talk at Pori Art Museum

Presented a brief overview of artistic and musical activities up to that point

http://www.poriartmuseum.fi/fin/peda/SATELLITE_PLATFORM_tiedote_eng.pdf

(December 2011 Hameenkyro, Finland)

Artist Work and Profile included in the Arteles Arts Catalog

http://www.arteles.org/artists_projects.html

(September 2009 Duluth, Minnesota)

Musical Performance in Spark Festival at University of Minnesota

Presented an improvised "experimental" music performance

http://blog.lib.umn.edu/sparkfst/info/SparkPage2010.pdf

(October 2010 Atlanta, GA)

Flux Projects

Artist piece entitled "Interactive Sonic Puppetry"

Sound Design and Composition

http://www.fluxprojects.org/flux2010/eiliyas.php

(October 2009 Leeds, U.K.)

Music Selected to Perform at Expo Leeds

Presented an improvised "experimental" music performance

(April 2003 Atlanta, GA)

Artwork presented at the Atlanta Contemporary Art Gallery

-Skill

HTML **

CSS**

Javascript*

Final Cut Pro***

Photoshop***

Illustrator**

Scrum

Language

- -English Native Speaker
- -German Language familiarity B1

Hobbies/Interests

Music, Arts, Culture, Theory, Ideas, Travelling, Literature, Food and Beverage